Experience working at a sub-acute facility for mental health and chemical dependency as well as a residential home for mental health disorders. History teaching and tutoring for classes at an undergraduate level. Psychological, nuerological, and statistical lab experience, including working with and guiding human participants and rodents through experimental procedures. Advanced Microsoft Office and statistical software knowledge including Matlab, SPSS, and others. Moderate computer programming knowledge (JAVA, C++, SQL, and others).

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**TEACHING ASSISTANT**, UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO, ALBUQUERQUE, NM, September 2015- May 2017 https://psych.unm.edu/graduate/index.html

- Designed lessons and substituted for professors, in-person teaching classes of 100+ students.
- Oversaw online and electronic aspects of classes of 1000+ students.
- Graded tests, homework, and other materials pertaining to undergraduate psychology courses.

LAB TECHNICIAN, UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO-DR. PENTKOWSKI, ALBUQUERQUE, NM, July 2015- May 2017

https://psych.unm.edu/people/faculty/profile/nathan-s.-pentkowski.html

- Specialized in research involving behavioral and neurological outcomes of drug use.
- Designed and conducted experiments including animal (rodent) behavioral and neurological testing.
- Analyzed and reported data using Excel, MatLab, SPSS, and other statistical programs.

**MENTAL HEALTH ASSOCIATE**, LIFEWORKS NW, TIGARD, OR, September 2014- February 2015 http://www.lifeworksnw.org/

- Taught and modeled lifeskills at a resident home for young adults dealing with mental health and behavioral disorders
- Created, organized, and ran treatment-based events for residents at site and in the local community.
- Administered daily and PRN medicine to residents.

MENTAL HEALTH SPECIALIST, PATHWAYS TREATMENT CENTER, KALISPELL, MT, October 2013- August 2014

http://www.kalispellregional.org/krmc/behavioral-health/pathways

- Worked with and collaborated as part of a treatment team to provide acute care and counseling for clientele of all ages suffering from chemical dependence and various mental health disorders (schizophrenia, bipolar, borderline, major depressive, etc.).
- Developed and led life-skill, wellness recovery action plans (W.R.A.P.), and other therapeutic groups for both adolescent and adult clientele.
- Coordinated with clientele to create and establish safety and further treatment based after-care plans.
- Received exemplary 6 month review marks for clientele respect and interaction, in particular with the adolescent clientele.

**RESEARCH ASSISTANT**, WILLAMETTE UNIVERSITY-DR. MILLER, SALEM, OR, September 2010-May 2013 http://www.willamette.edu/cla/psychology/faculty/miller/

• Developed experiment structure and implementation for multiple psychological research projects.

- Performed experiments on participants with ages ranging from college aged to the elderly.
- Collected and analyzed data using Excel, Systat, SPSS, and other computational programs.
- Wrote and reviewed papers submitted for publishing in psychology and neuroscience journals.
- Presented findings at a local research conference (Student Research Recognition Day).

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science: Psychology, University of New Mexico- Graduated May 2017, GPA: 4.18 Bachelor of Arts: Psychology, Willamette University- Graduated May 2013, GPA: 3.75